# **JOSEPH** MANCINI





## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Experienced software engineer with a passion for developing programs and APIs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. Well-versed in technology and programming to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company's organizational needs, highlight their core competencies and further their success.





631.662.9785



mancinij@udel.edu





Based out of NYC Metro Willing to Relocate

## **EDUCATION**

#### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE**

University of Delaware Computer Science May 2018

#### WEB APPLICATIONS

Columbia Engineering Coding Boot Camp Current

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- Vue/React/JavaScript
- Flutter/Dart
- Java
- MySQL
- Bash/Zsh

#### **PROJECTS**

- Presentation at BAE Systems, Inc. for summer 2017 project. Created a conference room locator in HTML for their site's homepage website.
- Programmed an iOS application called "Mad Hops - Are You Mad Yet?" Code written in Swift in Xcode. Graphics rendered in Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop.

# JOB EXPERIENCE

2021 - 2023

#### Software Developer

ClearVision Optical I Hauppauge, NY

- Launched Web Apps using React and Vue along with Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS and styled components for front-end and Axios to connect to the MySQL database for the back-end.
- Developed cross-platform applications using Flutter/Dart.
- Assisted with the front-end of our new Ordering App using Flutter/Dart for sales representatives in
- Created Restful APIs using PHP and Laravel.
- Deployed Webhooks using Python and Flask in AWS.

2020 - 2021

## **Software Engineer**

Nouveau Elevator I Long Island City, NY

- Assisted in developing a Custom Touchless Link Solution™ elevator system to comply with new Covid-19 regulations.
- Developed and implemented a script to reduce time of each Custom Touchless Link Solution™.

2018 - 2020

## **Software Configuration Manager**

BAE Systems, Inc. I Greenlawn, NY

- Build software/firmware to verify builds are reproducible and target files match.
- Write scripts to automate builds and other tasks.
- Track software/firmware changes throughout multiple programs.
- Manage release repositories to release builds efficiently for production floor use and/or shipment to
- Proficient in working with GIT/GForge/JIRA/Bitbucket, ClearCase/ClearQuest, Visual Studios and Microsoft Office.

2017 - 2018

## **Software Engineering Intern**

BAE Systems, Inc. I Greenlawn, NY

- Added support for new hardware on the Navy's P8 program production tool using Java. Worked in Netbeans/Visual Studio and SmartSVN repo.
- Worked in a Linux environment and updated expect scripts.
- Initialized cybersecurity investigation for products.

2016

## **Teaching Assistant**

University of Delaware I Newark, DE

Hosted labs, graded projects and held office hours twice a week.